

Avinash Adluri

Full Stack Developer



Professional Summary

Experienced React/Node Developer with 10 years in the industry and high-level proficiency in the following programs: Javascript, React, React native, Node, Angular, MongoDB, SQL, IONIC, Cordova, expertise with HTML and CSS seeks to establish a career as the Full Stack Developer in IT industry. I am very familiar and experienced with Web Application Architecture and have worked with a good number of successful development teams.



Work History

2017-10 -Current

Senior Developer

Cognizant - Australia, Sydney, NSW

- Collaborates with web app development team which includes Product Manager, Program Manager, Software Engineer, Quality Assurance, and Market Researcher in identifying software problems, testing methods, and best solutions.
- Actively participates and engages the Software Support team in resolving production issues.
- Improves and designs monitoring systems in order to address issues with systems stability and quality of data.
- Conceptualizes and designs testing protocols for the purpose of locating issues within the system.
- Used React, React native, Nodejs, MongoDB,
 HTML, CSS, JS, RWD, AWS, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp,
 Babel technologies.
- Trained 100s of colleagues in Reactis.

Techology Lead

Cognizant - India, Hyderabad, Telangana



Address

Veron St, Wentworthville Sydney, NSW, 2145

Phone

046-887-2009

E-mail

avinashadluri@gmail.com

Website

http://avinashadluri.com

Twitter

@avinashadluri

LinkedIn

avinashadluri



HTML/CSS/JS



React



Node



Redux Thunk/Saga



Angular



IONIC/Cordova



MongoDB/SQL/GraphQL



React Native



2014-06 -2017-10

Good

- Designed and developed efficient and maintainable software according to the business objectives and needs of the company's various clients.
- Designed and developed effective app-based solutions to address the problems and concerns of the company's clients.
- Studied, evaluated, and proposed solutions to complex architectural challenges for the purpose of introducing new features.
- Integrated app-based solutions with databases, file systems, and cloud-based systems.
- Immediately attended to all reported customer issues regarding app-based and software solutions; delivered software patches when needed.
- Used HTML, Css, JS, Angularis, React, Nodejs, MongoDB, Phonegap, IONIC, Cordova, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack.
- Worked as an Academic Trainer.

2009-06 -2014-04

Web Developer

Valuepitch ETechnologies - India, Mumbai, Maharastra

- Developed app-solutions using a variety of languages, frameworks, and platforms such as Javascript, CSS, and HTML.
- Collaborated with a team of experts to design and develop a web application.
- Worked closely in the planning, design, and delivery of software products and services.
- Presented software design issues, questions, and suggestions for the purpose of arriving at alternative courses of action.
- Provided assistance to Customer Support when troubleshooting technical issues of clients.

Webpack/Grunt/Babel
Good

REST APIs





Education

2005-05 -2007-05 Master of Science: Computer Science

Kakatiya University - Warangal - Telangana - India

2002-06 -2005-04 Bachelor of Science: Maths, Physics, Computer Science

Kakatiya University - Warangal - Telangana - India



Accomplishments

- As an Academic trainer, trained 100s of new joiners in front end development technology.
- Trained senior developers in React.
- Took 100s of interviews to lateral entry candidates.
- Developed few apps which are used in day to day lives.
- Excellent speaker, self motivator.



Certifications

2016-10

React Udemy Certification

2016-12

Node Udemy Certification

2020-01

AWS Developer - In progress



Interests

•

Own Blog

•

Mobile apps

Cricket

Tech gadgets